A Guide to the Arlington County Public Schools, 1909-2005
Arlington Public Library, Center for Local History
- Individual Schools
  - Fairlington
    - Correspondence and Memos, re: school closing 1973-1975 (Box 21)
    - Memos, re: renting school facilities 1976 (Box 21)
    - School Survey 1976 (Box 21)
  - Hoffman-Boston
    - Dedication, February 1953 (Box 21)
    - Evaluation 1953 (Box 21)
    - Events 1954 (Box 21)
    - Feasibility Study 1965 (Box 21)
  - Glencarlyn
    - Report on Proposed Additions 1973 (Box 21)
  - Gunston
    - Ground breaking program 1949 (Box 21)
    - Recreation Club 1957-1958 (Box 21)
    - School Schedule 1957-1958 (Box 21)
    - Gunston Globe 1959-03-25 (Box 21)
  - James Madison
    - Neighborhood School Advisory Committee 1975 (Box 21)
  - Jamestown
    - Memorial letter concerning Kathleen Jefferson 1976 (Box 21)
  - James Monroe
    - Influenza immunization study 1952-1953 (Box 21)
    - Parent's Handbook 1950 (Box 21)
    - Progress Reports 1950 (Box 21)
  - John Marshall
    - Correspondence, school lunch program 1955 (Box 21)
  - Kenmore
    - Article 1960 (Box 21)
    - Program of studies 1987-1988 (Box 21)
    - Seventh Grade program 1977 (Box 21)
  - Langston
    - Dedication 1953 (Box 21)
  - Oakridge
    - Letter to Editor 1951 (Box 21)
    - Memo, Oakridge Advisory Committee Appointment 1954 (Box 21)
    - Opening Program 1951 (Box 21)
  - Page School
    - Handbook 1972-1973 (Box 21)
  - Patrick Henry
    - Speeches 1950-10-18 (Box 21)
    - Yearbook 1985-1986 (Box 21)
  - Reed (a.k.a. Walter Reed)
    - Court cases (Box 21)
    - Clippings (Box 21)
    - Closing (Box 21)
    - Handbook/Directories 1970/71-1975/76, 1983/84 (Box 21)
    - Literary magazine 1980-1981 (Box 21)
    - Proposals for buildings (Box 22)
    - Self-study Report 1975-1976 (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 22)
  - Stratford
    - Course of study 1955 (Box 22)
    - Dedication (Box 22)
    - Magazine article 1954 (Box 22)
    - Signpost 1951 (Box 22)
    - Yearbooks (in vault) 1961-1977 (Box 22)
  - Swanson
    - Program of Studies 1987-1988 (Box 22)
    - CD-ROMs (Box 22)
  - Taylor
    - Handbook/Directory 1978-1981, 1985-1988 (Box 22)
    - Handbook/Directory 1988-1993 (Box 22)
    - Handbook/Directory 1995-2001 (Box 22)
    - Handbook/Directory 2001-2002 (Box 22)
    - Tiger's TAle (student creative writing) 1979, 1981, 1983-1984 (Box 22)
    - Tiger's Tale 1985, 1987 (Box 23)
    - Tiger's Tale 1988 (Box 23)
    - Tiger's Tale 1989 (Box 23)
    - Tiger's Tale 1990 (Box 23)
    - Non-School Awards to Students 1988 (Box 23)
    - 50th Anniversary Questionnaire Response 2004 (Box 23)
  - Thomas Jefferson
    - Brochure (Box 23)
    - Program of Studies 1987-1988 (Box 23)
  - Wakefiled
    - "American School Board Journal" 1955-12 (Box 23)
    - Brochure 1955 (Box 23)
    - Correspondence 1955 (Box 23)
    - Directory, students 1968-1969 (Box 23)
    - Handbook 1971-1972 (Box 23)
    - Industiral Arts Curriculum, n.d. (Box 23)
    - Program of studies 1987-1988 (Box 23)
    - Reunion directories 1958-1978, 1968-1983 (Box 23)
    - Reunion directory, class of 1963 1963 (Box 23)
    - "Signal" 1954-1955 (Box 23)
  - Washington-Lee (Washington-Liberty)
    - Athletic schedule 1994 (Box 24)
    - Class of 1954 1954 (Box 24)
    - Comencement exercise program 1941 (Box 24)
    - Commencement program and news photo 1951 (Box 24)
    - Feasibility study, wing renovation 1952 (Box 24)
    - Washington Lee Highlighter 1992 (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 24)
    - Newsletter, Crossed Sabres 1954-1955, 1966-1967 (Box 24)
    - The Penman 1967-1969 (Box 24)
    - The Penman 1969 (Box 24)
    - Photographs (Box 24)
    - Program of studies 1987-1988 (Box 24)
    - Student bill of rights (Box 24)
    - Cookbook 1927 (Box 24)
  - Williamsburg
    - Patriot 1962 (Box 24)
    - Program of studies 1987-1988 (Box 24)
  - Wilson (previously Fort Myer)
    - Photographs 1910 (Box 24)
    - Letters, re: school name change 1926 (Box 24)
  - Woodmont
    - Advisory committee list 1975-1976 (Box 24)
    - Annual school plan and plan assessment 1977-1980 (Box 24)
    - "The Best of Woodmont," literature magazine (Box 25)
    - Census records 1980 (Box 25)
    - Census worksheets 1980 (Box 25)
    - Dedication 1973 (Box 25)
    - Graduation programs 1974-1981 (Box 25)
    - Lease of Woodmont facility 1983 (Box 25)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 25)
    - Photographs (Box 25)
    - Planning, construction, and equipment records 1969-1972 (Box 25)
    - Renovation project 1970 (Box 25)
    - School closing records 1979-1980 (Box 25)
    - "Woodmonitor," literature magazine 1964, 1981, 1982 (Box 25)
    - "Woodmont Chatter" 1980-1982 (Box 25)
  - Yorktown
    - Dedication Program 1961 (Box 25)
    - Program of studies 1987-1988, 1989-1990 (Box 25)
    - School Calendar 1987-1989 (Box 26)
    - Graduation Program 1994 (Box 26)
  - Multiple Schools
    - Letter concerning enrollment in multiple schools (Box 26)
    - Financial quotes for multiple school attendance (Box 26)
    - Maury-Clay-Fillmore School, architect study (Box 26)
  - Photographs, additional
    - Various schools (Box 26)
    - Various schools (Box 26)
    - Clay-Fillmore Elementary class photos (Box 26)
    - Clay-Fillmore Elementary class photos (Box 26)
    - Long Branch Elementary class photos (Box 26)
    - Long Branch Elementary class photos (Box 26)
    - Maury Elementary class photos 1969-1970, 1970-1971 (Box 26)
    - Maury Elementary class photos 1970-1971, 1971-1972 (Box 26)
- Parent-Teacher Associations and Council of PTAs
  - Ashlawn P.T.A.
    - Meeting schedule 1971-1972 (Box 26)
  - Barcroft P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1953, 1972 (Box 26)
  - Barrett P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1968-1970 (Box 26)
    - Bulletins 1951, 1968 (Box 26)
    - Correspondence and resolution 1955-1956 (Box 26)
  - Cherrydale P.T.A.
    - Bylaws 1961, 1966 (Box 26)
    - History 1971 (Box 26)
    - Cherrydale School Advisory Committee Records 1956-1966 (Box 26)
    - Minutes 1916-10/1920-06 (Box 26)
    - Minutes 1920-09/1921-06 (Box 26)
    - Minutes 1921-09/1922-06 (Box 26)
    - Minutes 1922-10/1923-06 (Box 26)
    - Minutes 1923-10/1925-06 (Box 26)
    - Minutes 1925-10/1927-06 (Box 27)
    - Minutes 1927-10/1929-05 (Box 27)
    - Minutes 1936-1947 (Box 27)
    - Reports of Committees 1956-1957 (Box 27)
    - Executive Board Minutes 1961-06/1962-06 (Box 27)
    - Executive Board Minutes 1962-08/1963-06 (Box 27)
    - Executive Board Minutes 1963-09/1964-06 (Box 27)
    - Executive Board Minutes 1964-09/1966-05 (Box 27)
    - Executive Board Budget and Membership 1966-1969 (Box 27)
    - Bulletins 1962-1969 (Box 27)
    - Correspondence 1917-1919, 1921, 1957-1965 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous 1958-1963 (Box 27)
    - Scrapbooks 1929-1960 (Box 27)
  - Claremont P.T.A.
    - Bylaws 1953-1976 (Box 27)
    - Handbooks 1969, 1975 (Box 27)
    - Histories 1952-1966 (Box 27)
    - Minutes of Executive Board and General Meetings 1952-05/1955-05 (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Executive Board and General Meetings 1955-08/1961-05 (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Exectuive Board and General Meetings 1961-09/1964-06 (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Executive Board and General Meetings 1964-09/1967-05 (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Executive Board and General Meetings 1967-09/1971-11 (Box 28)
    - Minutes of Executive Committee and Treasurer's Reports 1973-1977 (Box 28)
    - Bulletins and Newsletters 1952-1957 (Box 28)
    - Bulletins and Newsletters 1958-1966, 1969, 1970 (Box 28)
    - Bulletins and Newsleters 1974-1975 (Box 28)
    - Clippings 1952-1961 (Box 28)
    - Photographs 1960-1976 (Box 28)
  - Clay and Clay-Fillmore P.T.A.
    - Henry Clay Twitter 1952 (Box 28)
    - Clay-Fillmore P.T.A. Handbook 1969-1970 (Box 28)
  - Fairlington P.T.A.
    - Bylaws 1959-1977 (Box 28)
    - P.T.A. Handbooks 1952-1965 (Box 28)
    - P.T.A. Handbooks 1966-1977 (Box 29)
    - History of Fairlington School and Community 1973 (Box 29)
    - Minutes of Executive Board/Executive Committee 1952-1955 (Box 29)
    - Minutes of Executive Board/Executive Committee 1960-09/1969-06 (Box 29)
    - Minutes of General Membership Meetings 1952-10/1967-05 (Box 29)
    - Minutes of General Membership Meetings 1967-09/1977-05 (Box 29)
    - Minutes of Executive Board/Executive Committee 1969-09/1974-06 (Box 29)
    - Minutes of Executive Board/Executive Committee 1974-09/1979-05 (Box 29)
    - Deposit Authorization 1960 (Box 29)
    - Budgets 1974-1977 (Box 29)
    - Audit 1976-1977 (Box 29)
    - Documents and Correspondence, re: P.T.A. Tax Exemption 1976-1979 (Box 29)
    - Bulletins 1948-1963 (Box 29)
    - "The News" 1969-1979 (Box 29)
    - Correspondence 1958-1979 (Box 29)
    - Reports (General) 1966-1969 (Box 30)
    - Reports (General) [1] 1973-1977 (Box 30)
    - Reports (General) [2] 1973-1977 (Box 30)
    - Reports of Working Committees 1960-1973 (Box 30)
    - Questionnaire, re: Drew School Desegregation [1] 1970 (Box 30)
    - Questionnaire, re: Drew School Desegregation [2] 1970 (Box 30)
    - School Closing and Consolidation Information Records 1973-1979, n.d. (Box 30)
    - Statistical Work Papers 1973-1976 (Box 30)
    - Clippings 1967-1978 (Box 30)
  - Glebe P.T.A.
    - Glebe School Dedication Program 1971 (Box 30)
  - Glencarlyn P.T.A.
    - Handbook (Box 30)
  - Gunston P.T.A.
    - Handbook, Bylaws, Bulletin 1957, 1970-1971 (Box 30)
  - Patrick Henry P.T.A.
    - Information sheet, undated (Box 30)
  - Highlands P.T.A.
    - Constitution 1947 (Box 30)
  - Stonewall Jackson P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1968-1970 (Box 31)
    - Newsletters 1951-1952, 1955, 1968, 1970 (Box 31)
    - Letter 1955 (Box 31)
  - Jamestown P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1970-1971 (Box 31)
  - Kenmore P.T.A.
    - Bulletin, Handbook 1969, 1971 (Box 31)
  - Francis Scott Key P.T.A.
    - Directories and Reports 1969-1970 (Box 31)
    - Clippings 1969, 1981 (Box 31)
  - Robert E. Lee P.T.A.
    - Bylaws 1965 (Box 31)
    - Handbooks 1957-1965, 1970 (Box 31)
    - History 1927-1943 (Box 31)
    - History 1947-1952 (Box 31)
    - History 1957-1964 (Box 31)
    - Minutes of Executive and Regular Meetings 1950-05/1961-03 (Box 31)
    - Minutes of Executive and Regular Meetings 1961-04/1962-06 (Box 31)
    - Minutes of Executive and Regular Meetings 1962-09/1963-10 (Box 31)
    - Minutes of Executive and Regular Meetings 1964-01/1965-04 (Box 31)
    - Treasurer's Reports 1944-1965 (Box 31)
    - Correspondence 1961-1963 (Box 31)
  - Long Branch P.T.A.
    - Letter 1987 (Box 31)
  - James Madison P.T.A.
    - Letter, Newsletter 1955, 1971 (Box 31)
  - George Mason Center P.T.A.
    - Parents' Handbooks 1969-1970, 1971-1972 (Box 31)
    - Newsletters 1970-1971 (Box 31)
  - Maury P.T.A.
    - Parents' Handbook 1971 (Box 31)
  - McKinley P.T.A.
    - Newsletters 1969-1970 (Box 31)
  - James Monroe P.T.A.
    - Bylaws and Officers 1950-1959 (Box 31)
    - Newsletters 1950-09/1951-05 (Box 31)
    - Newsletters 1951-09/1954-05, 1955-02 (Box 31)
  - Nottingham P.T.A.
    - Parents' Handbooks 1969-1971 (Box 32)
    - Newsletters 1967, 1969, 1971, 1982 (Box 32)
  - Oakridge P.T.A.
    - Parents' Handbook 1968 (Box 32)
    - Newsletters 1951-1952, 1954 (Box 32)
  - Page P.T.A.
    - Handbooks and Newsletter 1968-1971 (Box 32)
  - Randolph P.T.A.
    - Bulletin, Handbooks 1952, 1971-1972 (Box 32)
  - Walter Reed P.T.A.
    - Bylaws 1957 (Box 32)
    - Handbook 1968-1969 (Box 32)
    - School History 1921-1941 (Box 32)
    - School History 1938-1950 (Box 32)
    - Historian's Reports 1943-1955 (Box 32)
    - Historian's Reports 1956-1964, 1974-1980 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee and Membership Meeting Minutes 1952-09/1954-06 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee and Membership Meeting Minutes 1954-08/1956-06 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee and Membership Meeting Minutes 1956-08/1958-06 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee and Membership Meeting Minutes 1956-08/1958-06 (Box 32)
    - Executive Committee and Membership Meeting Minutes 1958-08/1959-05, 1960, 1983 (Box 32)
    - Hospitality Committee Summary 1955-1956 (Box 32)
    - Bulletins 1954-11/1956-12 (Box 32)
    - Bulletins 1979-1984 (Box 32)
    - Westover Merchants Careers Projects 1978-1979 (Box 33)
    - Volunteer Information 1979 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence (General) 1955 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence, re: School Consolidation 1979-1980 (Box 33)
    - School Consolidation Reports, Speeches, etc. 1979-1980 (Box 33)
    - Fair Photographs 1979 (Box 33)
    - Photographs (General) 1983-1984 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1979-1980 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1982-09/1982-11 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1982-12/1983-01 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1983-02/1983-03 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1983-04 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1983-05/1983-06 (Box 33)
    - Scrapbook 1983-1984 (Box 33)
  - Stewart-Tuckahoe P.T.A.
    - Bulletin and Parents Handbook 1968-1970 (Box 33)
  - Stratford Junior High P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1954-1972 (Box 33)
    - Publications 1951-1956, 1971 (Box 33)
    - Correspondence 1951-1954, 1958 (Box 33)
  - Swanson Junior High P.T.S.A.
    - P.T.S.A. Bulletins 1971, 1992 (Box 34)
  - Taylor P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1968-1972 (Box 34)
    - Correspondence, Executive Board Minutes 1981 (Box 34)
    - Taylor Tattler 1978-04/1983-04 (Box 34)
    - Taylor Tattler 1984-09/1983-04 (Box 34)
    - Taylor Tattler 1988-10/1992-06 (Box 34)
    - Taylor Tattler 1992-09/1994-10 (Box 34)
    - Taylor Tattler 2003-10/2004-04 (Box 34)
  - Wakefield P.T.A.
    - Handbook 1953-1955, 1960, 1968-1971, 1992-1993 (Box 34)
  - Washington-Lee P.T.A.
    - Parents Handbooks 1933-1941, 1949-1950, 1963-1971 (Box 34)
    - Newsletters 1952-1956, 1968-1969, 1971, 1991-1994 (Box 35)
    - Newsletters 1994-11/1997-06 (Box 35)
    - Newsletters 1997-11/1999-06 (Box 35)
    - Newsletters 1999-09/2001-06 (Box 35)
    - Newsletters 2001-10/2003-06 (Box 35)
    - Newsletters 2003-09/2005-04 (Box 35)
  - Williamsburg P.T.A.
    - Newsletters 1970-1971 (Box 35)
  - Woodlawn P.T.A.
    - Handbook 1970-1971 (Box 35)
  - Woodmont P.T.A.
    - Enabling Documents including Bylaws 1967, 1977 (Box 35)
    - Executive Board, Officers and school Staff 1974-1982 (Box 35)
    - Handbooks 1969-1975 (Box 35)
    - Directories 1959-1962, 1971-1977 (Box 35)
    - Activity Records 1962-1977 (Box 35)
    - Minutes of Executive Committee and General Meetings 1968-1972 (Box 36)
    - Minutes of Executive Committee and General Meetings 1973-1977 (Box 36)
    - Minutes of Executive Committee and General Meetings 1975-1977 (Box 36)
    - Treasurer's Reports 1935-1954 (Box 36)
    - Treasurer's Reports 1956-1964 (Box 36)
    - Treasurer's Reports 1965-1977 (Box 36)
    - Budgets 1969-1977 (Box 36)
    - Newsletters 1969-1976 (Box 36)
    - Newsletters 1977-1981 (Box 36)
    - Correspondence 1961-1976, 1981 (Box 36)
    - Miscellaneous Notices and Flyers 1954-1956, 1970-1979 (Box 36)
    - Insurance Policy 1979 (Box 36)
    - Auction 1962 (Box 36)
    - Outdoor Center Project Proposal 1974 (Box 36)
    - Spring Festivals, Quilting Project and Miscellaneous 1979-1981 (Box 37)
    - Petition Opposing School Closing 1980 (Box 37)
    - School Closing Papers 1981-1982 (Box 37)
    - Clippings on Closing 1981 (Box 37)
  - Yorktown P.T.A.
    - Handbooks 1968-1972 (Box 37)
    - Newsletters 1969-1971 (Box 37)
  - Arlington County Council of P.T.A.s
    - Bylaws (Box 37)
    - Council and County Officers 1948-1956 (Box 37)
    - Council and County Officers 1971-1980, 1985 (Box 37)
    - History of County Council of PTAs 1949 (Box 37)
    - Leadership Guide 1955, n.d. (Box 37)
    - Budgets 1948-1949, 1958-1960, 1970-1971 (Box 37)
    - Bulletins 1949-1966 (Box 37)
    - Bulletins 1969-1980 (Box 37)
    - Correspondence 1973, 1976 (Box 37)
    - Reports and memos 1948-1956 (Box 37)
    - Reports and memos 1962, 1969, 1976-1977, 1980 (Box 38)
    - Newspaper clippings, re: integrating P.T.A. meetings 1957-1959, 1970-1977 (Box 38)
    - Newspaper clippings, miscellaneous 1950-1957 (Box 38)
    - Press Releases (Box 38)
    - Report from Committee for Educational Excellence 1983 (Box 38)
    - Virginia Congress of Parents and Teachers 1972, 1984, n.d. (Box 38)
- Oversize Material
  - Oversize 1
    - Claremont photo classbooks 1958-1970
  - Oversize 2
    - Claremont photo classbooks 1971-1976
  - Oversize 3
    - Cherrydale PTA minutes vol. 1 (1929-1947) and vol. 2 (1947-1960) 1929-1960
  - Oversize 4
    - Lee PTA Treasurer's reports, 1944-1965; Lee PTA meeting minutes, 1950-1961 1944-1965
  - Oversize 5
    - General
    - Washington and Lee "Crossed Sabres"
    - Wakefield "Signal"
  - Also see RG 7 - Map 1 (drawer #8